[Music]
hello and welcome to iphone markets
continuing with our series on
expectations for the fourth quarter
today we will look at what the insurance
sector has in store for us
in the quarter let us look at the life
insurance segment first
we expect a strong rebound in the life
insurance segment
although a low base of the march 2020
quarter would also have a role in it
the annual premium equivalent growth for
our coverage companies
is seen at 26 percent on a y basis
we believe the aggregate growth in new
business premium
and value of new business is pegged at
34 percent by you buy
on an average focus on non-fire products
would be a key driver of this growth
the trends in growth of ape and vnb
could be divergent for individual
companies
we believe sbi life will lead the way
with the strongest firewire growth
in ape and bnb at 44 and 46
respectively for hdfc live
vnb growth will be driven by robust
growth in ape
along with healthy margin expansion in
case of icici prudential life
slower growth in ape would be offset by
continuous margin expansion
resulting in 20 percent yui growth in
its vnb
we believe aggregate growth in renewable
premium is estimated
at the healthy rate of 14 on a wi-fi
basis
led by focus in high persistency we
expect the slowdown in retail protection
to continue in the quarter
sharp growth witnessed in credit life
during q3 could continue in the fourth
quarter as well
what are the factual factors to watch
out for growth outlook on savings
products
particularly non-power savings products
impact on the youtube segment due to the
new tax review
and recent tax revenue on high ticket
your lips
management insights on the competitive
landscape as well as pricing
in retail protection and change in
distribution strategies of the companies
on a dream position of lockdown in some
states
general insurance we expect ici salomon
and bajaj alliance general insurance to
grow their gdpi
by nine percent and five percent on a y
basis respectively
this is a tad low when compared to the
gdpi growth for the industry
at 12 in the quarter
we believe icici nombat is likely to
block double digit growth in the final
segment while the health segment could
see mixed results
growth in the retail indemnity segment
of the company is likely to be offset by
softness in the benefit segment
increase in frequency of covert claims
could lead to higher loss ratios
in the health segment for icici lombard
but would be offset by the motor segment
allowing it to report around 100 percent
combined ratio
thanks for tuning in if you like this
video subscribe to afl markets